Guide to the St. Peters Evangelical (Slovak) Lutheran Church, Uniontown, Pa. Records, 1887-1979 AIS.1980.22
ULS Archives & Special Collections
St. Peters Evangelical (Slovak) Lutheran Church, Uniontown, Pa. Records
1887-1979
ULS Archives & Special Collections
St. Peter's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Uniontown, Pa.)
AIS.1980.22
1 microfilm_reel (252 frames)
This microfilmed collection contains the records of St. Peters Evangelical (Slovak) Lutheran Church. The records cover the period 1887-1979 and include baptisms, confirmations, communions, marriages, deaths, anniversary booklets, and lists of council members and pastors.
History
St. Peter's Evangelical Lutheran Church was organized in 1894 in Connellsville, Pa., by the Rev. C. L. Orbach. A charter was granted in 1896 under the name "St. Peter's Slovak Evangelical Church of the Augsburg Confession of Connellsville, PA" A chapel and parsonage, located at 210 E. Main St., were purchased in 1896. In 1906, the congregation dedicated a new church on Porter Ave.
In 1918, the congregation bought a church at 171 Connellsville St. in Uniontown. The church, built in 1909, was formerly occupied by the Hungarian Reformed Church. By 1924, Uniontown had become the center of the church's activities. The state granted a new charter to the church in 1934 and the Connellsville church was sold in 1940. Additions were made to the church in 1969 and a new parsonage at 33 Wilmac St. was purchased in 1979.
Brief histories of St. Peter's can be found in Series III on microfilm and in the case file.
Scope and Content Notes
The records in this collection span the years 1887-1979. Baptisms, confirmations, marriages and deaths are fairly well represented for all of those years. Other records from 1951-1968 include church council members and communions. Portions of Series I, Combined Church Records, are in Slovak. Series II includes a list of pastors, 1898-1965, as well as an annual summary for 1953. Series III consists of Anniversary booklets for 1969 and 1979 (75th and 85th anniversaries). Duplicate anniversary booklets for those years can also be found in the case file.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Microfilmed by the Archives of Industrial Society in August 1980.
Existence and Location of Originals
Original records retained by St. Peter's Evangelical Lutheran Church, Uniontown, Pa.
Previous Citation
St. Peters Evangelical (Slovak) Lutheran Church, Uniontown, Pa. Records, AIS.1980.22, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
St. Peter's Evangelical (Slovak) Lutheran Church, Uniontown (Fayette County), Pa., Records, 1887-1979, AIS Micro 80:22, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Connellsville (Pa.) -- Church history; Pennsylvania -- Church history; Uniontown (Pa.) -- Church history; Lutheran Church -- Pennsylvania; Ethnic groups; Churches and Synagogues; Baptismal records; Church records and registers -- Pennsylvania; Fayette County (Pa.) -- Church history; St. Peter's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Uniontown, Pa.); St. Peter's Slovak Evangelical Church of the Augsburg Confession (Connellsville, Pa.)
- Combined Church Record, 1887-1950; I.
  - Baptisms, 1887-1949 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Confirmations, 1898-1950 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Marriages (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Deaths, 1899-1950 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
- Parish Register, 1898-1968; II.
  - Pastors, 1898-1965 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Church council members, 1951-1955 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Members, 1955-1967 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Communions, 1958-1968 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Baptisms, 1951-1964 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Confirmations, 1951-1965 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Marriages, 1951-1964 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Funerals, 1951-1964 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Annual summary, 1953 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
- Anniversary Booklets, 1969, 1979; III.
  - v. 1 "75th Anniversary 1894-1969 Diamond Jubilee" (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - v. 2 "85th Anniversary 1894-1979" (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 9, Reel 1)